Atul Chaudhary

845-671-1611 | pachaudhary12@gmail.com

Executive Summary

24 years of experience in the planning and execution of tasks involving the migration of Windows/Linux servers from P2V or V2V; migration of Windows legacy and Current to new Active Directory OUs, combining Group Policies and ensuring tighter security of applications and systems ensuring compliance with the company's GIS requirements. Experience in designing Active Directory and resolving Domain Controller issues. Experience in ensuring deployment of packages to systems while working with the business to ensure maximum uptime of critical systems during the development of Covid-19 vaccines. Experience in working well with vendors, customers, and team members from different departments to ensure success of a migration or upgrade. Experience in creating/destroying infrastructure in AWS/Azure using Terraform. Experience in using DevOps tools such as Ansible, chef and Puppet in the automatic deployment and configuration of applications. Experience in deploying servers in Azure/AWS. Experience in completing deployments and upgrades according to ITIL Processes.

Technical Skills

DevOps (Terraform, Powershell, Python, Ansible, Ansible Tower, Git, JSON, Team Foundation Server), Azure, AWS, ESX Virtual Center, PlateSpin, Jira (Epic, Story), Blade Logic BSA/CLM/Atrium, Orchestrator/AR/ITSM/SRM/BCO/ADDM/CMDB, AppZero, Windows 2012/2016 Server, UNIX/LINUX, SQL, Citrix XenApp, iVanti Management Suite, Remote Desktop Gateway, Print Server, WSUS, SMTP Server

Protocols/Switches:

TCP/IP, WINS, DNS, HTTP, HTTPS, TELNET, FTP, TFTP, LAN/WAN, HTML, POP3, IMAP, IMAP4, SMTP, NNTP, LDAP, MIME, S/MIME, Ethernet

Accomplishments:

- > Saved 30% in annual budget spending for AXA Equitable
- Improved system performance by 50% for AXA
- Enhanced security of legacy environment by setting up WSUS
- Improved deployment efficiency on legacy environments through automation using Powershell scripts, Ansible and Tower

Professional Experience

Pfizer - Pearl River, NY

August 2017 to December 2020

Windows Systems Engineer (Consultant)

- Perform upgrades, deployments, and troubleshooting according to ITIL Processes
- ➤ Enhanced automation of deployable packages leveraging PowerShell scripts
- Improved legacy OS Security through Group Policy modifications
- Increased automation script reliability
- Improved consistency and efficiency of deployable packages remotely to clients
- Increased reliability of automatic creation of Remote Desktop Gateway Access Policies

Windows Systems Engineer/Site Reliability Engineer

- Enhanced Virtual Template Promotion Process
- Improved efficiency and success rate of automated application installation scripts
- Increased efficiency in maintenance of PowerShell scripts
- Improved reliability of new AppHost environment on internal platform-based cloud environment

Hughes/EchoStar – Germantown, MD

May 2015 to September 2015

Windows Migrations Lead/Windows SME

- > Improved team communication
- Enhanced efficiency of application migration project
- Improved daily customer communication of the ongoing project

AXA Technology Services - Jersey City, NJ

2006 to 2015

Technical Lead (Automation)

- ➤ Improved communication with team members relating to various Technical Project/Initiatives
- Enhanced processes to ensure on time and efficient delivery of projects to customers
- Drove initiative to improve efficiency and maximum uptime of production Windows/ESX during upgrade or patching
- Improved the deployment automation time
- > Drove the KMS introduction, architecture, documentation, and deployment
- > Improved reliability and efficiency of new and existing SQL, and Windows environments based on vendor recommended Best Practices
- Drove the Azure/AWS Cloud Service project

Additional Work Experience/Career

NMHC RX, (TECHNICAL LEAD SERVER SUPPORT/NETWORKING), Port Washington, NY, 2003 to 2005 Integramed (3RD LEVEL SUPPORT), Purchase, NY, 2002 to 2003 Worldco, LLC, (2ND/3RD LEVEL SUPPORT), New York City, NY, 2000 to 2002 Bloomberg, LP, (SECOND/THIRD LEVEL SUPPORT), New York City, NY, 1997 to 1999 GTE SERVICE CORP (Windows Engineer/Management), Stamford, CT, 1997 to 1997 BBDO, NY (Systems/Network Engineer), 1995 to 1997

Education & Professional Training

Education:

MBA, Technology Management (2011), University of Phoenix - Phoenix, AZ Bachelor of Science, Electrical Engineering (1994), New York Institute of Technology - Long Island, NY,

Certifications:

Network+, A+, MCP Windows

Affiliations:

AXA RESCUE TELECOM